Palestine Statehood Committee "Concerning the campaigns for a Jewish Army; to save the Jewish people of Europe and the establishment of a Hebrew Republic in Palestine" Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- 1981 September Addition, 1939-1942
  - Public Record Office - Foreign Office
    - Document 312. National Headquarters of the Committee for a Jewish Army (1 page), 1947 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/448 76147 P.
    - Document 313. National Headquarters of the Committee for a Jewish Army (1 page), 1947 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/448 76147.
  - National Archives - Department of State
    - Document 1. Murray, Wallace to Cordell Hull (5 pages), 1942 June 2 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1812 1/5. Includes 1 attachment: to Hackworth, G. H. (4 pages), 1942 May 29.
    - Document 2. Murray, Wallace to Cordell Hull (1 page), 1942 July 14 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1812 3/5 PS/LPC.
    - Document 3. To The President (9 pages), 1942 July 31 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: F.W.867N.01/1812 3/5 PS/LBC.
    - Document 4. Murray, Wallace to Cordell Hull (1 page), 1942 August 5 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1812 4/5 PS/LBC.
    - Document 4a. Wise, Stephen to Sumner Welles (2 pages), 1942 September 2 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/3050 (?).
    - Document 5. Halifax, Viscount to Sumner Welles (2 pages), 1942 November 13 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/11-1342 OS/VJ. Includes 1 attachment: Welles, Sumner to Viscount Halifax, 1942 Nov 10.
    - Document 6. Halifax, Viscount to Sumner Welles (2 pages), 1942 December 30 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/12-3042. Includes 1 attachment: from Hopkinson, Henry (11 pages), 1942 Dec 9.
    - Document 7. Murray, Wallace to Sumner Welles (1 page), 1943 January 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/12-3042 CS/H. Includes 2 attachments: Welles, Sumner to Mr. Murray, 1943 Jan 2; Welles, Sumner to VIscount Halifax, 1943 Jan 3.
    - Document 8. Murray, Wallace to Miss Clarkson (5 pages), 1943 January 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-2942 CS/H. Includes 2 attachments: A. L. C. to Mr. Murray, 1943 Jan 5; Hopkinson, Henry to Sumner Welles, 1942 Oct 29.
    - Document 8a. Harrison to C. Hull (2 pages), 1943 January 21 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 9. Hull, Cordell to American Embassy (1 page), 1943 February 16 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/3603 PS/VMC.
    - Document 10. J. F. C. to Mr. Berle (5 pages), 1943 March 9 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1879 PS/ERW PS/DAB. Includes 1 attachment: Kettaneh, Francis to Harry, 1943 Mar 8.
    - Document 11. Long, B. to Mr. Travers (22 pages), 1943 May 4 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Reproduced from the collections of the Manuscript Division, Library of Congress, box number 203. 21 attachments, including various documents.
    - Document 12. Hull, Cordell to Francis Biddle (1 page), 1943 August 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.20/207 PS/DAB.
    - Document 13. EU:REAMS:TMT to S. Gray (3 pages), 1943 August 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1964 PS/JB. Includes 2 attachments: Welles, Sumner to S. - Mr. Gray, 1943 Aug 6; Hull, Cordell to Dr. Max Lerner 1943 Aug 7.
    - Document 14. Winant to Cordell Hull (1 page), 1943 August 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4124 PS/ATB. Regards Emerson's salary.
    - Document 15. Hull to Winant (2 pages, missing), 1943 August 10 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 16. Hull, Cordell to Winant (2 pages), 1943 August 10 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4214 PS/MAS.
    - Document 17. Rifkin, Maurice to C. Hull (1 page), 1943 August 11 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1922 PS/RN.
    - Document 18. Long to Brandt (1 page), 1943 August 12 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Reproduced from the collections of the Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 19. Osinoff, A. to C. Hull (1 page), 1943 August 12 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01.1913 PS/JB.
    - Document 20. Welles, Sumner to B. Long (2 pages), 1943 August 13 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Memorandum of conversation between Welles and the Dutch Ambassador, London. Reproduced from the collections of the Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 21. Harrison to C. Hull (2 pages), 1943 August 22 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 862.4018/2285 PS/MO.
    - Document 22. Long to FDR (2 pages), 1943 August 22 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 23. Long to Hull (2 pages), 1943 August 26 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 24. Brandt to Bell (1 page), 1943 August 26 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 25. Hull, C. to Max Lerner (1 page), 1943 September 1 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4435 PS/BMB.
    - Document 26. Long, B. to Congressman Celler (3 pages), 1943 September 1 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 27. Long, B. to Peter Bergson/Ira Hirschman (3 pages), 1943 September 1 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 28. Long, B. to Mr. Travers (1 page), 1943 September 2 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Regards repling to a British memorandum on refugees. Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 29. Hull, C. to Steinhardt (missing), 1943 September 4 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Regards Hirschmann's going to Turkey.
    - Document 30. Steinhardt to Hull (1 page), 1943 September 7 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 31. Conversation between Long and Goldman (4 pages), 1943 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4542 PS/JF. Regards relief through the ICRC; a little memo by Long attached.
    - Document 32. Long, B. to S. (1 page, missing), 1943 September 20 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Reply to: Joe Davies suggests Hull speak at Madison Square Garden on Nov. 16, 1943 to commemorate 10th Anniversary of American recognition of the Soviet Union.
    - Document 33. EU:RE Murphy: Itk (probably Intelligence) to Long (5 pages), 1943 September 23 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Regards CJA and ECSJPE, an inimical analysis of the people behind these activities and especially P. Bergson. Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 34. MHM to President (3 pages), 1943 September 27 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 35. Merriam, G. P. to Memo (1 page), 1943 September 29 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1999 1/2.
    - Document 36. Long, B. to Rabbi Wise, Dr. Goldmann (2 pages), 1943 October 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 37. McIntyre, M. H. to B. Long (6 pages), 1943 November 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4854 PS/MJN. Includes 5 page telegram to FDR signed by Ben Hecht and Sigrid Undset.
    - Document 38. E. S. to B. Long (1 page), 1943 November 19 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2010-1/2. Attachment missing.
    - Document 39. Kuppinger, E. D. to B. Long (3 pages), 1943 November 22 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/5029 PS/HW (?).
    - Document 40. Travers, H. K. to Ben Hecht (2 pages), 1943 December 4 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 840.48 Refugees/4854.
    - Document 41. From Wilson, E. M. (6 pages), 1944 January 10 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2220 PS/?. Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
    - Document 42. Alfange, Dean to Cordell Hull (1 page), 1944 January 17 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 43. NEA:EMW:GH to Jerusalem (5 pages), 1944 January 24 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.20/213.Includes 2 attachments: Nemzer, Louis to Messrs. Merriam and Wilson (4 pages), 1944 Jan 22; S. Merlin's hand written note.
    - Document 44. Murray, Wallace to Stettinius (3 pages), 1944 February 17 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 45. Stettinius, E. R. to Robert Wagner (1 page), 1944 February 21 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2201.
    - Document 46. Stettinius to Jerusalem (1 page), 1944 March 6 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 47. NE:EMW:MW to Jerusalem (1 page), 1944 April 4 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 48. Wilson, E. M. to Jerusalem (4 pages), 1944 May 19 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
    - Document 49. From Wilson, E. M. (4 pages), 1944 May 23 (Box 16, Folder 1, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2350 800.01B11. Includes 3 attachments. Regards registration of Peter Bergson and his groups under the Foreign Agents Registration Act.
    - Document 50. Stettinius, E. to Wallace Murray (1 page), 1944 May 24 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2353 PS/LC.
    - Document 51. Stettinius, E. to Wallace Murray (4 pages), 1944 May 26 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2349 PS/LC. Includes 3 attachments: Nahum Goldmann's letter to Stettinius; Nahum Goldmann's letter to Henrik de Kauffmann; Press release.
    - Document 52. Hull, Cordell (2 pages), 1944 May 29 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 53. Murray, Wallace to E. Stettinius (1 page), 1944 May 31 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2352 PS/LC.
    - Document 54. Murray, Wallace to E. Stettinius (4 pages), 1944 June 2 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867.01/6-144. Includes 3 attachments dated June 1 regarding Peter Bergson.
    - Document 55. Department of State to Mr. Murray (8 pages), 1944 June 2 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2346. Includes 7 attachments: Segal, Louis to E. Stettinius, 1944 May 25; press release, 1944 May 22; Zaritsky, Max to American League, 1944 May 22; Stettinius, E. to Mr. Segal, 1944 Jun 7.
    - Document 56. Silver, Abba Hillel to Adolph Berle (2 pages), 1944 June 5 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/6-544. Includes 1 attachment.
    - Document 57. Berle, A. A. to Rabbi Silver (1 page), 1944 June 14 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 58. Conversation with Edgar Turlington, attorney for Peter Bergson (3 pages), 1944 June 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/6-1744.
    - Document 59. From Wilson, E. M. (2 pages), 1944 June 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 800.01B11 Registration/6-1744 PS/VL. Registration of Peter Bergson and his group with the Department of Justice.
    - Document 60. Bergson, Peter to Cordell Hull (5 pages), 1944 June 19 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/6-1944 OMM. Includes a 4 page letter and 1 enclosure.
    - Document 61. Proskauer, J. M. to Cordell Hull (3 pages), 1944 June 20 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: FW 867N.01/2359. Includes 2 attachments: Proskauer, J. M. to Peter Bergson, 1944 Jun 20; Hull, Cordell to Judge Proskauer, 1944 Jun 29.
    - Document 62. Bishop, W. W. to Mr. Merriam (2 pages), 1944 June 28 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 63. Biederman, N. to A. A. Berle, Jr. (1 page), 1944 July 3 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-344(?).
    - Document 64. E. S. to Mr. Murray (6 pages), 1944 July 12 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-1244. Includes 5 attachments: Mrs. ROosevelt to Mr. Stettinius, 1944 Jul 8; American League to Mrs. Roosevelt, 1944 Jul 2; Stettinius to Miss Thompson, 1944 Jul 17; G. P. M. to Alex Wilf, 1944 Jul 14.
    - Document 65. Edelman, Sam to Secretary of State (2 pages), 1944 July 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-1444. Includes 1 attachment.
    - Document 66. Yale, William to P. W. Ireland (5 pages), 1944 July 15 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-1544 OS/D. Memo with 4 page attachment.
    - Document 67. Warren, George L. to J. J. Smertenko (1 page), 1944 July 19 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 68. Merriam, G. P. to Smertenko, J. J. (1 page), 1944 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 69. Wilson, E. M. to F. O. (1 page), 1944 July 24 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 70. Warren, G. to Mr. Berle (2 pages), 1944 August 4 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/8-244.
    - Document 71. Kohler, Foy D. to Peter Bergson (1 page), 1944 August 5 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 72. From HPT (1 page), 1944 August 8 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-1544 CS/O.
    - Document 73. Wilson, E. M., memo (5 pages), 1944 August 10 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/8-1044.
    - Document 74. Korff, Dr. to E. R. Stettinius (5 pages), 1944 August 15 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/8-1544. Includes 4 attachments on efforts to persecute Peter H. Bergson.
    - Document 75. Anderson, W. S. to Mr. Lyon (1 page), 1944 September 7 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/9-744 CS/VC. Regards Hebrew Committee of National Liberation.
    - Document 76. Wilson, E. M., memo (6 pages), 1944 September 13 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Regards Zionist attitude toward Palestine.
    - Document 77. Murray, Wallace to Mr. Long (2 pages), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 78. Poison Gas discussion - Joint Chiefs of Staff (17 pages), 1944 September 16-October 5 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      - Bergson, Peter H. to Joint Chiefs of Staff (2 pages), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source numbers: B-96936, B-96937
      - Bergson, Peter H. to Joint Chiefs of Staff (2 pages), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source numbers: B-99902, B-99903
      - McFarland, A. J., Brig. Gen., memo for Joint Chiefs of Staff (1 page), 1944 September 19 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-96753
      - Reply to Hebrew Committee of N. L. (2 pages), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source numbers: B-99900, B-99901
      - (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-102618
      - From Redraft (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-103049
      - Arnold, H. H., General to Joint Chiefs of Staff (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-102617
      - McFarland, A. J. to Admiral Leahy (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source numbers: B-102924, B-102514
      - To J. C. S. (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: 385-3
      - From J. C. S. (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-107500
      - Admiral Leahy to H. C. of N. L. (1 page), 1944 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-103967
      - Memo for record (1 page), 1944 October 5 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-107499
      - Handy, Lieutenant General Thomas T. to Brig. General McFarland (1 page), 1944 October 5 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        Source number: B-104404
      - Handy, Lieutenant General Thomas T. to Brig. General McFarland (1 page), 1944 October 5 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Document 79. E. M. W. to Mr. Warren (7 pages), 1944 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-1144 CS/D. Includes 2 attachments: Bergson, Peter H. to Cordell Hull (5 pages), 1944 Oct 11; Kohler, Foy D. to Peter Bergson, 1944 Dec 8.
    - Document 80. To Murray, Mr. (6 pages), 1944 November 30 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 3571, 867N.01/11-2944 EG. Includes 2 attachments: from Hassett, Wm. D., 1944 Nov 30; Bergson, Peter H. to President (4 pages), 1944 Nov 29.
    - Document 81. Warren, George L. to Peter Bergson (1 page), 1944 December 9 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 82. Memo of conversation between Merriam and Egyptian Ambassador about the ALFP offer to pay for the defense of Hakim and Ben Tzuri (2 pages, missing), 1945 January 3 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1-345 EIS.
    - Document 83. Watson, Hathaway to Mr. Murray (2 pages), 1945 January 26 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1-2445. Includes 1 attachment: letter from P. Bergson to E. Stettinius dated Jan 24.
    - Document 84. ALFP to Secretary of State (4 pages), 1945 January 31 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/1-5145.
    - Document 85. Wilson, E. M., memo of conversation (2 pages), 1945 January 31 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: FW 867N.01/1-3145 CS/D.
    - Document 85A. W. L. to Joseph C. Grew (2 pages), 1945 February 20 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/2-2045 CS/D.
    - Document 86. Grew, Joseph C. to Senator Langer (1 page), 1945 February 27 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number undecipherable.
    - Document 87. Merlin, S. to A. MacLeish (25 pages), 1945 May 1 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/5-145 CS/MAU. Includes 2 attachments: 23 page letter from P. Bergson to Chaim Weizmann; 1 page letter from MacLeish.
    - Document 88. Henderson, Loy to J. C. Grew (2 pages), 1945 May 12 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/5-1245 CS/LE.
    - Document 89. Grew, J. C. to Senator Green (2 pages), 1945 May 16 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/5-1645 CS/LE.
    - Document 90. Hanson, Haldore to A. MacLeish (3 pages), 1945 July 11-12 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/7-1245 CS/LE.
    - Document 91. MacLeish, Archibald, memo for the file (1 page), 1945 July 14 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
    - Document 92. Gillette, Guy to James F. Byrnes (3 pages), 1945 August 18 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/8-1845 CS/LF.
    - Document 93. Henderson, Loy to Mr. Secretary (2 pages), 1945 August 24 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: FW 867N.01/8-1845 CS/LE.
    - Document 94. Merriam, Gordon P. to Mr. Reams (2 pages), 1945 September 13 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/9-1345 CS/MDR ?. Includes 1 attachment: letter Sep 12 from Guy Gillette to James F. Byrnes.
    - Document 95. Henderson, Loy to Mr. Acheson (2 pages), 1945 September 14 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/9-1445 CS/MDR. Includes 1 attachment.
    - Document 96. Henderson, Loy to Mr. Acheson (1 page), 1945 September 21 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/9-2145 CS/LF.
    - Document 97. Beam, R. C. to Secretary of State (3 pages), 1945 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/9-1645 CS/LE. Includes reply to Mr. Beam, 1945 Oct 10.
    - Document 98. Bergson, Peter to Harry S. Truman (1 page), 1945 October 1 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-145 CS/LE.
    - Document 99. Beltroy, Manuel (telegram) to The President (1 page), 1945 October 4 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: FW 867N.01/10445 CS/S?
    - Document 100. Translation of telegram Oct 4 (1 page), 1945 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-445 CS/LE.
    - Document 101. Stern, J. David to James F. Byrnes (1 page), 1945 October 16 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-1645 CS/VJ.
    - Document 102. Connelly, Matthew to Secretary of State (1 page), 1945 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/10-1145. Includes 2 attachments: 2 page letter from Charles Buckley to Harry S. Truman, 1945 Oct 11; 1 page memo from Miss Reminger to Mrs. Denhan, 1945 Oct 30.
    - Document 103. O'Connell, Joseph to James F. Byrnes (2 pages), 1946 August 30 (Box 16, Folder 2, Reel U11)
      Source number: 867N.01/8-2646 CS/A. Includes 1 attachment: Aide Memoire from British Embassy (source number: 867N.01/8-646 CS/HH).
    - American Jewish History, American Jewish Historical Society quarterly publication, 1981 March (Box 16, Folder 3, Reel U11)
- Additional materials, 1944-1945, undated; Accession 2004-M-023
  - American League for a Free Palestine [minor publications], 1944-1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)